Eric Perret

P: (650) 241-1836

A: San Francisco, CA E: resume@ericperrets.info W: www.ericperrets.info

SUMMARY

Highly skilled software engineer with over 20 years of experience designing, developing, and leading the creation of complex web applications. Proven ability to optimize performance, create user-friendly interfaces, and automate tasks to improve efficiency. Extensive knowledge of full-stack development, system design, and agile methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce, San Francisco, California

Principal Member of Technical Staff September 2018 - present

Led a team of engineers in designing, developing, and maintaining Salesforce's Aura and Lightning Web Runtime frameworks used by millions of users daily.

- Improved key app' performance by 20% through code optimizations, architectural improvements, network enhancements, and strategic caching strategies.
- Championed security best practices and ensured seamless integration with various software components.
- Designed and implemented a new authentication mechanism for web applications.
- Mentored and fostered the growth of junior engineers within the team.

Lead Member of Technical Staff December 2015 - September 2018

Led the technical design & development of a critical component within Salesforce's Sales product.

- Successfully integrated Salesforce with Microsoft and Google calendar products.
- Designed and implemented a new system architecture to improve scalability & performance.
- Collaborated with designers to build intuitive and user-friendly interfaces.
- Developed core backend services, including data synchronization and event processing.
- Ensured software quality through rigorous testing and debugging processes.

Software Engineering SMTS / Product Owner / UX / SysEng May 2014 - December 2015

- · Led a team of developers in building web applications to support Salesforce's cloud infrastructure.
- Owned product vision and ensured development efforts aligned with business objectives.
- Developed real-time web applications for infrastructure monitoring and capacity planning.
- Built web applications to automate server configuration tasks.

September 2011 - May 2014 SMTS, UI-Browser Performance Engineer Cloud Computing

- · Analyzed and optimized Salesforce's CRM UI performance for millions of users.
- Defined and implemented performance testing strategies to ensure new features didn't slow down the website.
- Collaborated with other teams to identify and resolve performance bottlenecks.

Aetna Inc., Hartford, Connecticut

Senior Application Developer May 2009 - September 2011

SYSTEM DESIGN & ARCHITECTURE

Performance Optimization

Network Optimization

Scalability

System Integration

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Java Spring

JavaScript

HTML/CSS

SQL **XML**

Angular/Polymer

Web Standards

Internet Protocols

USER EXPERIENCE (UX)

User-Centered Design

Prototyping

Accessibility

Usability Testing

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Agile Methodologies Team Leadership

Prioritization

TESTING

Unit

Integration

Performance

- Led a team that built a new web application, replacing 5 legacy applications.
- Designed features, user interface, and wrote front-end and back-end code.
- · Collaborated with business Application

UI Application Developer June 2005 - May 2009

Developed web-based applications used by thousands of employees.

- · Designed the application's user interface.
- Created guidelines for how to design user interfaces.
- Worked with business experts to figure out how the application should work.
- Created reusable JavaScript libraries.
- Wrote code for both the front-end and back-end.

DWM Inc., Latham, New York

Enterprise Application Developer May 2004 - May 2005

EDUCATION

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, New York

Master of Science, Information Technology May 2005

Concentration: Human-Computer Interaction (Usability)

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science May 2004

Minor: Information Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

- Human-Computer Interaction, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute
- Designing Accessible Websites (508), U.S. General Services Administration



COLOPHON

Date Mod.: 10/27/2024, 10:34:12

PM

Fonts: Helvetica-Light, Roboto